pos.com.my 2018-03-04

# 

PERSONAL DATA PROTECTION NOTICE
We comply with the Personal Data Protection Act 2010. This Personal Data
Protection Notice (“Notice”) informs you how we use your personal data based on
the following guiding principles:
            We use your personal data to provide you postal, courier and other
             transactional products and services which you request.
            We aim to continuously improve our products and services for you and will
             use your personal data to help us achieve this.
            We give you some control over the personal data we hold about you,
             including who is allowed to see it and how it is used.
            We will not use your personal data to contact you for direct marketing
             purposes without your consent.
            We will take reasonable care to safeguard your personal data through
             security policies and secure business processes.
This Notice applies generally to all products and services provided by Pos Malaysia
(consisting of Pos Malaysia Berhad and all its subsidiaries and related corporations
including but not limited to PSH Express Sdn Bhd, Datapos (M) Sdn Bhd, Digicert
Sdn Bhd, Pos Ar-Rahnu Sdn Bhd, Effivation Sdn Bhd, PSH Properties Sdn Bhd, PMB
Properties Sdn Bhd, Real Riviera Sdn Bhd, Pos Malaysia & Services Holdings
Berhad, PSH Capital Partners Sdn Bhd and PSH Venture Capital Sdn Bhd).
There may however be occasions where a different data protection notice will be
applicable for a specific transaction, and we will notify you accordingly. Please read
the terms of this Notice carefully before furnishing us with your personal data. By
furnishing us with your personal data or by continuing to use our products or
services, you are indicating to us that you agree and consent to the terms and
conditions of this Notice.
In respect of personal data of any Third Party Individual (defined below), you
warrant that you have obtained the relevant consent from the Third Party Individual
to furnish his/her personal data to Pos Malaysia and for Pos Malaysia to process
such personal data. You further warrant and undertake to furnish a copy of this
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                                 1

Notice to the Third Party Individual before providing Pos Malaysia with that Third
Party Individual’s personal data.
How we collect your personal data
Directly from you. We collect personal data that you provide to us when you use
any of our products, services, and website(s) or when you deal with us. This
includes information that you provide:
            When you request for any services or purchase any products from us;
            When you perform a transaction or contract with us;
            When you fill in manual forms and submit them to us;
            When you deal with us over the telephone, through email, through our
             website(s) or in person;
            When you take part in our customer surveys, competitions and promotions;
            When you use our services;
            When you visit our premises; or
            From correspondence you send to us including any enquiries or comments.
When you use our website. We may collect some information automatically when
you access our website(s) including:
            Information about your use of our products and services, including your
             browser type, operating system, platform, IP address, cookies, language and
             region; and
            Search queries you conducted on our website(s), pages and advertisements
             you viewed and links you clicked on while using our website(s).
From third parties. We may ask third parties for personal data about you, for
example, when we acquire third party marketing lists, or get authorisation for a
payment you make using a credit or debit card, or to complete a credit or fraud
check.
Corporate entities. Where we transact or contract with a corporate entity, that
corporate entity may provide us with your personal data in connection with a
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                               2

transaction or contract. That corporate entity is responsible for obtaining your
consent for disclosure of your personal data to us.
What personal data we collect
In this Notice, personal data means data we hold about you from which your
identity is apparent or can be reasonably determined. This includes:
            Your identification information such as name, identification number, gender,
             ethnic origin, nationality, date of birth, age and marital status;
            Your contact details such as address (residential, office or billing), telephone
             number(s), email address(es) and other contact details that you provide us
             from time to time;
            Your employment details such as your employer’s name, your position in the
             company, job description, the company’s address(es), telephone number(s),
             your income range and professional credentials or qualifications;
            Your payment details such as bank account number and credit or debit card
             details;
            Transaction-related information, including sender’s and recipient’s
             identifying information and contact details as well as personal data of
             individuals given by corporate entities in connection with a transaction or
             contract;
            Recording of telephone conversations;
            Personal data of your spouse, dependents or other third parties (“Third Party
             Individual”); and
            Additional information that you provide us when you transact or deal with
             us or when you visit us.
Why we collect your personal data
            To provide you with products and services. Note that the personal data we
             require may vary between transactions;
            To verify your identity and to minimize the risk of unauthorized access to
             your personal data when you deal with us;
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                                   3

            To enhance and improve your experience with us generally. When you
             indicate your preferences by filling in our forms, through your use of our
             website(s) or when you contact or deal with us directly, we will use this
             personal data to personalize our products and services to better meet your
             needs;
            To provide you with information or notifications about products and services
             that we or our agents, contractors, employees, associate companies, business
             partners or professional consultants of Pos Malaysia (“third party”) have
             selected and believe would be of interest to you (Please see the sections
             entitled “Who sees your data” and “Important information about opting-
             out”);
            To prepare any statistics or analysis or internal reports for market research
             purposes;
            To allow us to enforce our legal rights or to recover any debt owing by you to
             us;
            To keep your personal data secure and minimize the risk of unauthorized
             access to your personal data by using some of your personal data to verify
             your identify when you use our website(s) and customer service helpdesk;
            For security purposes when you visit our premises; and
            To ensure compliance with applicable laws and regulations.
Who sees your personal data
Your personal data may be used by all the companies within Pos Malaysia and DRB
HICOM Berhad’s related group of companies. Who sees your personal data depends
on the context in which you provided it and the purpose for which it is being used
(Please see the section entitled “Why we collect your personal data”).
Your personal data may be disclosed or transferred to a third party. This may
include outsourcing any of our business operations or functions to any third party
within or outside Malaysia. We may do this for the following reasons:
            To provide you with our products and services or perform a contract with
             you. Some of our products and services are provided in conjunction or
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                                 4

             collaboration with certain third parties, and we will need to disclose your
             personal data to them to provide you with the products and services. We may
             also share your personal data with certain third parties who have been
             engaged to perform our business functions;
            To provide you with information or notifications about our products and
             services that we or third parties have selected and believe would be of
             interest to you. If you have given your consent by choosing not to opt out
             when filling in our manual forms, using our website(s) or when you contact
             or deal with us directly, we may share some of your personal data with
             carefully selected third parties so that they can provide you with information
             about products and services that may be of interest to you;
            We may share your personal data with third parties (including the police and
             other law enforcement agencies) when we believe it is necessary to comply
             with the law or protect our or another person’s rights, property or safety. This
             includes exchanging data with third parties to protect against fraud and to
             reduce payment risks or disclosure of personal data to the police and other
             law enforcement authorities in connection with the prevention and detection
             of crime;
            We may share your personal data with regulatory bodies and agencies to
             ensure compliance with applicable laws and regulations; or
            If we sell or buy any business or assets, we may disclose your personal data
             to the potential seller or buyer of such business or assets.
We will only deal with third parties whom we trust will act in your best interest and
will treat your personal data with similar security controls that we apply ourselves.
Where we store and process your personal data
We generally store and process your personal data within Malaysia. However, the
personal data that we collect about you may be processed in, transferred to, or
stored at a destination outside of Malaysia. By filling in our manual forms, using our
website(s) or when you contact or deal with us directly, you agree to this processing,
transfer or storage outside Malaysia. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                                   5

your personal data is treated securely and in accordance with this Notice even when
your personal data is processed in, transferred to, or stored at a destination outside
Malaysia.
How long we keep your personal data
This depends on the context in which you provided your personal data and the
purposes for which we use it. Your personal data will be retained for as long as it is
reasonably necessary for such purpose (Please see the section entitled “Why we
collect your personal data”), or for such period as may be necessary to protect our
legal interest.
We will keep your personal data:
            For as long as it is reasonably necessary for us to provide you with our
             products and services you have purchased or requested, or for the
             performance of a contract with you;
            For marketing purposes to provide you with information about products and
             services that we or our third party business partners have selected and
             believe would be of interest to you until you choose to opt-out from allowing
             us to process your personal data for marketing purposes (Please see the
             sections entitled “Your rights to access and correct personal data” and
             “Important information about opting-out”);
            We may keep records of any transactions you enter with us for up to 7 years
             so that we can respond to any complaints or disputes which may arise. Where
             the records are the subject of legal investigations or proceedings, we will keep
             the personal data for longer periods; and
            We will keep your personal data for as long as it is required to comply with
             the law.
Your rights to access and correct personal data
In relation to our manual forms, you may access, correct or update your personal
data by filling in the Personal Data Access Request Form or Personal Data
Correction Form. These forms are available at www.pos.com.my or if you contact our
Corporate Compliance Department (please see the section entitled “Enquiries”) and
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                                   6

we will endeavour to comply with your instructions within 21 days of receiving
your completed form and the prescribed processing fee.
In relation to personal data provided to us through our website(s), you can access
the information at the [‘Edit Your Profile’] page (if any) or contacting our Corporate
Compliance Department. You can also use this profile page to change or delete this
information including the consent you have given us (Please see the section below
entitled “Important information about opting-out”) and we encourage you to do so
in order to ensure that the personal data we hold about you is up-to-date. Your
personal data can be deleted from the website(s)'s database by accessing the option
for 'My profile' once you have logged on to the website(s). Here you can select to
delete your account and cancel your registration with us. This however will not
delete your personal data that: (i) was not collected through our website(s); (ii)
which we need to continue to hold for the purposes specified above under the
section entitled “How long do we keep your personal data”; or (iii) is on third party
database not under our control.
In relation to personal data provided to us to use through our website(s), you can fill
in the relevant forms which are available online on our website(s) to request for
access or to correct your personal data.
You can request details of all the personal data that we hold about you, by
contacting our Corporate Compliance Department. Our Corporate Compliance
Department will send you the Personal Data Access Request Form and/or Personal
Data Correction Form which you should complete and return to them.
The charges for personal data access services are as follows:
       Personal Data Access Request for your personal data with a copy                -
        RM 10
       Personal Data Access Request for your personal data without a copy             -
        RM 2
       Personal Data Access Request for your sensitive personal data with a copy      -
        RM 30
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                            7

       Personal Data Access Request for your sensitive personal data without a copy -
        RM 5
These charges may be revised from time to time.
The contact details of the Corporate Compliance Department are set out in the
section entitled “Enquiries” below. Your right to access your personal data is not
absolute, and may be limited by the Personal Data Protection Act 2010.
Important information about opting-out
The personal data that we ask you to provide may either be mandatory or optional,
and may differ depending on the particular product or service. Mandatory personal
data is information required for the processing of the transaction, or provision of
products and services, or performance of a contract. Optional personal data is
information you voluntarily provide to us, which we may process during the
transaction or to provide you with other products and services. Fields requiring
mandatory personal data will be indicated in our manual forms and registration
forms on our website(s).
If you choose not to furnish any mandatory personal data requested or wish to
withdraw your consent or significantly limit the processing of your personal data,
you agree that (notwithstanding any agreement between you and us) we shall be
entitled to cease the provision of any products or services to you without incurring
any liability whatsoever for any losses which you may suffer as a result of such
cessation.
By not ticking a clearly displayed "opt-out" box, we will assume we have your
implied consent to process your personal data pursuant to the terms of this Notice
and to receive information about products and services that we or our third party
business partners have selected and believe would be of interest to you until you
choose to opt-out from allowing us to process your personal data entirely or to limit
the processing of your personal data for marketing purposes.
You may choose to limit the processing of personal data or withdraw your consent
to process your personal data by any one of the following means:
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                            8

            Sending us a written notification to the contact details provided in the section
             entitled “Enquiries”;
            Ticking the “opt-out” box in our manual forms for our products and/or
             services;
            Filling in our “Opt-out” card; or
            Editing your profile on our website(s) (if any).
We will endeavour to comply with your request within 21 days / as soon as we are
reasonably able to do so.
In relation to our website(s), you may withdraw or add your consent at any time
through the “Edit your profile” page (if any) or by contacting our Corporate
Compliance Department. When you choose to withdraw your consent by choosing
to opt-out in our website(s), this would apply only to your personal data stored in
our website(s)'s database. It would not apply to personal data which you have
provided to a business in Pos Malaysia through another channel other than our
website(s) or if your personal data has been passed to third parties with your
consent.
In relation to links to other sites found on our website(s), please note that personal
data provided to these third parties are not under our control and responsibility and
you may need to contact them directly if you wish to withdraw your consent for
their continued use of your personal data.
Please note that once we receive confirmation that you wish to withdraw your
consent for marketing or promotional materials/communication, it may take up to 21
days for your withdrawal to be reflected in our systems. Therefore, you may still
receive marketing or promotional materials/communication during this period of
time. Please note that even if you opt-out from receiving marketing or promotional
materials, we may still contact you for other purposes in relation to the products and
services you transacted with us.
Websites
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                                 9

In relation to our website(s), some of the information will be gathered through the
use of "cookies". Cookies are small bits of information that are automatically stored
on a person’s web browser in their computer that can be retrieved through the
website. Such information, for example, may be a user’s password that is stored to
avoid having to retype it during subsequent visits to a site. Should you wish to
disable these cookies, you may do so by changing the setting on your browser.
Note that personal data transmitted electronically will not be 100% secure. We will
not be liable for any breach of security unless we have been negligent.
Our website(s) may also contain links to other sites controlled by a third party.
Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.
We are not responsible for how these other companies or organizations collect, use,
disclose, or secure the information that you provide them. This Notice applies solely
to information collected by website(s) maintained by Pos Malaysia. If you choose to
access a third party site linked to our website(s), you do so at your own risk and
subject to any terms of service or privacy policy (if any) associated with such third
party websites.
Where Pos Malaysia is processing your personal data on behalf of another person or
entity, the processing of your information would depend on the privacy practices of
that person or entity. This would not be under our control or responsibility. You
should contact them directly on the processing of your personal data.
Revisions to the Notice
Our Notice may be revised from time to time and if there is any revision, it will be
posted on our website(s) and/or other means of communication deemed suitable by
us.
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                            10

Enquiries
If you have any enquiries or complaints concerning this Notice, please contact our
Corporate Compliance Department at:
Pos Malaysia Berhad
Corporate Compliance Department
Tingkat 8, Ibu Pejabat Pos
Kompleks Dayabumi
50670 Kuala Lumpur
Attn: Personal Data Protection Compliance Officer
Tel: 03 – 2267 2040
Email address: pdpapos@pos.com.my
 This Notice is made available in the national and English languages. In the event of
any discrepancies, the English language version of the Notice shall prevail.
This Personal Data Protection Notice was last updated on: 7 January 2015
                                         - End -
Pos Malaysia Berhad (229990-M)
Level 8, Pos Malaysia Headquarters
Dayabumi Complex,
50670 Kuala Lumpur
+603 2274 1122
www.pos.com.my
                                            11
